SENIOR SCRUM MASTER Summary

Senior Scrum Master with 10 years of total experience including 6+ years of helping team delivering large-scale software and Web development projects on time and on budget by effectively collaborating, facilitating, and leading multiple scrum teams with a servant leadership style. Accomplished Scrum expert seeking a new opportunity to grow and provide value. As a scrum master I am ready to bring value to any team by facilitating all scrum ceremonies and reducing waste through evolving teams into thinking lean. I am results-driven and have a proven record of transforming organization into healthy growing agile environments. I am a focused individual with a constant willingness to learn and continuously improve my agile skills and knowledge. Professional Scrum Master (PSM) â£" Scrum.org

Skills

- Expert at driving the adoption, and enforcement of Scrum rules.
- Made proactive usage of Agile governance and Agile Frameworks: Scrum, Kanban, XP, SAFe
- Highly skilled in team facilitation, conflict resolution, implementing best practices, team empowerment and creating a culture of transparency
- Capable of bringing overwhelming awareness to projects and applying expert judgement to remove and escalate impediments while keeping team members focused and delivering success in rapid involving environment
- Mentoring team of diverse cultures
- Exceptional problem solving and sound decision-making capabilities.
- Ability to inculcate new relevant skills with ease in a time sensitive environment.
- TECHNICAL SKILLS
- EVANT SKILLS
- Project Management

- Release Management, Strategic Planning, Business and Risk Analysis, Project Portfolio Estimation, Budgeting and Forecasting, Conflict Resolution
- Project Lifecycle Methodologies
- Agile (Scrum Framework), Waterfall
- Project Management tools
- JIRA, VersionOne, MS Project Management, Confluence, Rally, matrix, QuickBase
- Operating Systems
- Window 7, Window 10, Mac OS, Linux, Ubuntu
- Microsoft Office products
- MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Visio

Experience

Cox Enterprises | Euless , TX Senior Scrum Master 11/2019 - Current

- Servant leader for agile teams within the DevOps by ensuring clear communication and by integrating Agile & Lean principles into team practices for better adoption and faster delivering
- Evaluate the Agility Maturity Assessment results to understand opportunity areas in teams' maturity and provided recommendation
- Mentor Scrum masters on how to empower their teams to be more productive
- Responsible for Sprint planning, managing product backlog, holding daily scrum meetings, removing impediments and mentoring scrum team members
- Responsible to have all the required artifacts created to comply with the quality assurance audit process
- Act as a shield between the software development teams and any distracting influences
- Provide risk management and issue / problem resolution proactively
- Ensures teams' continuous improvement in adherence to defined organizational goals (retrospective, minimize WIP, increases team productivity, visible teamwork, increases flow, ensures pull system)
- Attend Scrum of Scrums (S2) meeting where teams' progress, impediments, dependencies, risks (using ROAM) and downstream impacts are addressed
- Organize team around PI Objectives publish them for visibility and transparency and participate in PI-Planning
- Manage and optimize the flow of value through the program using various tools, such as the Kanban and information radiators
- Coach the team on Agile values, principles and techniques i.e., User Stories, TDD, BDD, Continuous Integration, Continuous Testing, Continuous Delivery, Continuous Deployment and Automated Testing
- Create metrics and charts using EAZYBI to support Identity Access Management and Security Groups Automation within DevOps thus reinforced continuous delivery to increase SLA
- Worked with stakeholders in understanding the project, communicating progress and changes in schedule
- Conduct Root Cause Analysis for incidents to help fix the issues and to present same issues from happening anew
- Proactively and effectively communicate in various verbal and written formats with internal and external stakeholders on project scope, budget, and schedule status of implementations

Cb Richard Ellis | Sunrise, FL Scrum Master 09/2017 - 11/2019

- Served as a scrum master for projects by providing servant leadership, guidance and leadership to ensure the team-maintained focus on quality and continue delivery by coaching them on Agile values and principles and scrum framework to increase execution, adoption and team productivity
- Facilitated scrum ceremonies, sprint planning, daily standups, review demo, retrospective, backlog refinement session
- Using the scrum framework as well as other software Development Life Cycle methodology
- Collaborated with peers to coordinate cross team dependencies and deliverables
- Facilitated User Acceptance Testing (UAT)
- Produced and maintained artifacts to help communicate team success, deliverables and timeline
- Support the product owners and Business Analyst in Backlog management and maintenance
- Remove impediments, resolution in a timely and cost-effective manner
- Used JIRA to create transparency and report metrics and artifacts by maintaining the product Backlog, Epics, user stories, Issues, velocity,

Burndown chart, DOD, Acceptance Criteria

- Created transparency with stakeholders via the use of JIRA
- Worked closely with Product Owner, Project Manager and technical lead to ensure that the work is strategical
- Facilitated high level planning to establish the project baseline and sprint schedule for functional and non-functional user stories
- Ensure that transparency is established along artifacts with the use of JIRA and Confluence
- Assisted Agile release team to implement branching and merging strategies
- Utilize Agile governance to ensure project transparency and team alignment, Successfully completed 2 rotations in IT and Finance reporting to the VP of procurement and the head of IT
- Scrum Master co-leading a cross-functional team to identify Database synergy between Henkel and Sun Products merger and acquisition
- Assessed the Scrum Maturity of the team and organized and coached the team to higher levels of maturity, at a pace that is sustainable and comfortable for the team and organization
- Removed impediments or guided the team to remove impediments by finding the right personnel to remove the impediment
- Built a trusting and safe environment where problems can be raised without fear of blame, retribution, or being judged, with an emphasis of healing and problem solving
- Organized and led release planning for a delivery of group of multiple scrum teams
- Assigned to a product feature group resulting in a creation of a project road map
- Utilized JIRA and RALLY to track team progress
- Met goal of addressing and resolving issues within 24 hours
- Managed sprint backlogs, iterations as well as facilitating daily standup meetings
- Work with HR to recruit, interview and onboard new upcoming PRISM F class â6"2 days interview process

Vanir | San Antonio, TX Program 09/2016 - 09/2017

KeyTech.Solutions | City, STATE Project Coordinator 06/2012 - 08/2016

- Managed cross-functional teams of 8 people located in China and the USA in the launch for Vaseline skin care products in Asia
- Increased gross margin by implementing strategic network and products deliverables and cut project cost by 20%
- Managed stakeholders via alignment on deliverables, risk and cost associated with projects
- Awarded team's MVP for going above and beyond project's action standards
- Owned and Managed global skin care department database to track spending, tracking entire team and projects' budget and provides budget review to team's leadership.

Education and Training

University of Connecticut M.S in Business Analytics and Project Management 03/2016 University of Maryland Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering 05/2012